The reason for which you need to buy a mostly customers buy the aftermarket unit is for simple reasons.
Sometimes they do want to upgrade, their systems and especially if you want to add an iPod to the stock radios.
They usually the stock radios don't have these features available.
On when you buy and after market radio a like I told you before they're equip already there.
Also when you want to do a big system like on add a, two woofers, you want more base in your system.
It's kind of hard to do it when you have a stock radio because they don't usually have a, the features for them like a radio like this they already have it.
If you look at it like I said again, they have the inputs for it so that make it easier for us to be able to hook a big system to them.
Also the sound quality it's a lot better than just having a stock radio.
If stock radio is the radio that come from the manufacture from the dealer so the basically what they have, they only have the AM FM and CD player.
That's all it is they don't have any type of a features that you can add to them so if you want to upgrade this radio you actually need to the dealer and the dealer charge so much that a, customer instead of a spending that much money on that they can actually save a lot of money and get something that is probably is going to do a lot better job with a lot less money.